# **BRADEN OGNOSKIE**

Full Stack Developer

Security Clearance: Secret(Active)

(210) 500-0386 · bradenjognoskie@gmail.com · LinkedIn · Github · Portfolio

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with a passion and solid foundation in front-end languages, libraries, and frameworks. Experienced in creating intuitive web applications and keen to grow within a collaborative team environment. Dedicated to continuous learning and applying emerging technologies to solve real-world challenges.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages/Technologies: HTML5 - CSS3 - SASS/SCSS - Bootstrap-JavaScript - ES6 - AWS-AJAX - Git - React.js - Rest API - APIs -Software development life cycle- Engineering techniques -Spring Boot-SQL Database-Agile development methodologies- Back-end - Debug - Web services- UI/UX design - Responsive design - Front-end development-Technology adoption-Responsive web design -Programming languages -Automation- Node.js-Impact software- Debugging - Test-driven development- Project development- Software design-Modern frontend tooling-Agile methodology-Career networking- Web accessibility-Technical support- Debugging software-Cross-browser compatibility-JSON-Design patterns- Machine learning-Interaction design-Operating systems-UI design-Wireframes-Version control- Mobile apps- reliability engineering-Unit testing-Application development-CI/CD-Research-Sweeping-Terraform- Refactoring-Interviewing-Microservices-System design-Technical design-Digital Experience- Teaching experience-MacOS-Webpack-Web standards

## SOFT SKILLS

Skills: Collaboration- Brainstorming - Interpersonal communication skills - Teamwork - Critical thinking - Integrity - Digital experience -Innovative - Solving problems - Professionalism - Willingness to learn - Solve complex problems - Strong problem-solving skills - Learning new technologies -Agility - Committed - Ability to lead - Compassion - Mentorship - Cross-functional team -Constructive feedback -Analytical Skills - Innovation - Adaptable-Reliability - Flexible - Community Events-Collaborating-Follow instructions- Resolving issues-Invision-Usability-Sustainability-Invent-Resilient-Flexibility-Coaching-Adult learners-Empathetic

**Exposure to:** Agile Management Tools - KanBan for Workflow - Project Management Tools - Github Pages - NPM - Scrum Stand Up - Documentation - Spring Framework - Agile Development - Search Engine Optimization

# **EDUCATION**

### Codeup

Certification of Completion

May 2023 - Oct 2023

This 5-month coding boot camp teaches full-stack software development through 670 contact hours of hands-on technical training (20% more time than 4-year degree majors require). Students hone skills in modern web technologies, computer science, software engineering, and application architecture while gaining project experience with pair programming, debugging, troubleshooting, agile project management, user stories, feature lists, UI/UX, wireframing, and relational database design.

# **DEVELOPMENT PROJECT**

**Dev Project Lister: Repository** 

A simplified version of Craigslist that allows users to post and browse advertisements. The project provides a functional and user-friendly platform for posting and browsing advertisements, while also providing me with experience in web development, database management, and software testing.

Skills: Agile methodology, Paired programming, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, MySQL, and jQuery.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Wilson County ESD #3**

Emergency Medical Technician- Basic

Nov 2021 - May 2023

- Provided basic life support and multiple treatment options to countless patients in a critical life threatening state.
- Been a part of multiple cardiac arrests, pediatric arrests, and critical trauma calls.
- Assisted ALS partners on multiple RSI/DSI treatments for patients in respiratory arrest.
- Administered a variety of different medications.
- Experienced in placing IOs (intraosseous access) and IVs (intravenous access).
- Able to perform in high stress environments and adapt to any changes in patient care.
- Maintained and in charge of thousands of dollars in equipment with no loss.
- Extensive knowledge on the pathophysiology and physiology of multiple diseases and life threatening injuries.

#### MILITARY EXPERIENCE

# U.S. Army

Machine Gunner / Sniper Team Leader

Aug 2017- Dec 2020

- Instructed personnel on ways to increase rifle marksmanship efficiency while proper use of PPE.
- Maintained half a million dollars of equipment with no loss.
- Provided protective overwatch for allied forces and delivered long range precision fire on key targets.
- Able to conduct reconnaissance and collect intel within enemy controlled territories.
- Maintained sniper rifles, machine guns, pistols and hand grenades while keeping accountability of all weapons.
- Quickly promoted to leadership position in recognition of strong work ethic.
- Conducted security operations in a foreign country.